# RYAN BURNETT

Mundelein, IL 60060 | Phone: 773-673-3982 | Email: ryanpburnett@yahoo.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-burnett-912b8667

Github: https://github.com/ryanpburnett | Portfolio: https://ryanpburnett.github.io/

#### SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer leveraging experience as an educator, composer and musician to create a creative, clean, and useful web experience for the end user. Previous experience in teaching with an ability to learn quickly and find creative solutions to problems.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Java

Technologies: ¡Query, Node, Express, React, Angular, MongoDB

#### EXPERIENCE

# Full stack developer Infosys

2021 – Present Remote / Lisle, IL

Full stack developer responsible for attending to the requirements of various client projects, fulfilling the criteria of user stories, and gaining skills necessary to work with relevant technologies on each project.

#### Key Accomplishments:

- Worked on three different teams using the Scrum framework
- Delivered working code, on time, and to specifications
- Improved code documentation

#### **PROJECTS**

Let's Go! | https://github.com/ryanpburnett/Project-3 | https://glacial-waters-54685.herokuapp.com

- This app will allow the user to be able to explore whichever city they're in on a bike, and find points of interest and rest stops along the way.
- Role Played: back end coding team, specifically working on GeoJSON and getting locations to render. Also did some front end work designing React components.
- Technologies Used: React, <u>Leaflet</u>, GeoJason, and MongoDB, and is deployed with Heroku.

LyricLysteners | https://github.com/ryanpburnett/lyric-finder | https://ryanpburnett.github.io/lyric-finder

- A lyric finder site that generates lyrics for any song, along with a QR code linking to related YouTube videos.
- Role Played: back end coding team, specifically implemented the QR codes generated for the site.
- This app uses the HappiDev API and the QR code generator API.

Chord Progression Generator | <a href="https://github.com/ryanpburnett/chord-progression">https://ryanpburnett.github.io/chord-progression/index.html</a>

- This site generates chord progressions, 12-tone rows, and single row rhythm matrices. Future iterations of this project will feature a play button with dynamically generated MIDI sound.
- Sole Developer; app is written in vanilla JavaScript.

#### PREVIOUS CAREER EXPERIENCE

# PK-8 general music teacher/choir director Pope Francis Global Academy

2018 – 2021 Chicago, IL

Elementary Music teacher responsible for teaching general music, directing the school choir. Communication is a key transferable skill from this role, as it was necessary for teaching a wide range of ages and skill levels, as well as being able to collaborate well with parents, other teachers, and administration for high quality outcomes. Being able to think well on my feet is another key skill transferable from this role, as lesson plans frequently need to be adapted to accommodate student learning.

## Key Accomplishments:

- Founded and taught the middle school coding program
- Founded and taught the school choir
- Founded and taught the after school guitar program
- Designed and directed assemblies throughout school year
- Collaborated with other teachers in designing and teaching cross-disciplinary classes
- Engaged in professional development, focusing on classroom management and curriculum development

# K-8 general music teacher/ Alfred Nobel Elementary School

2015 – 2018 Chicago, IL

Similar job description and responsibilities as above.

- Co-founded after school band
- Designed and directed assemblies throughout school year
- Directed music for graduation ceremony
- Coordinated and chaperoned field trips

#### **EDUCATION**

**Full Stack Web Development Certificate:** Northwestern University - Evanston, IL A 6 month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

#### Master's Degree in Music Education - Illinois PEL:

VanderCook College of Music - Chicago, IL

#### **Bachelor's Degree in Music Performance:**

Northeastern Illinois University - Chicago, IL